<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Posts on Alan&#39;s Blog</title>
    <link>https://tcode2k16.github.io/blog/posts/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Posts on Alan&#39;s Blog</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Mon, 23 Jul 2018 16:55:46 +0800</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="https://tcode2k16.github.io/blog/posts/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>Generals.io game bot</title>
      <link>https://tcode2k16.github.io/blog/posts/generals-io-bot/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 23 Jul 2018 16:55:46 +0800</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://tcode2k16.github.io/blog/posts/generals-io-bot/</guid>
      <description>Credit: dev.generals.io   What is Generals.io? Generals.io is a turn-based strategy game that can be played in the browser. Each player starts out with one grid on a large map that is called the general. The goal of the game is to expand and eliminate other players&amp;rsquo; generals. Once a player&amp;rsquo;s general gets taken, the player loses the game, and in the end, the last player standing wins the game.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Crossctf Final 2018 Writeup</title>
      <link>https://tcode2k16.github.io/blog/posts/crossctf-final-2018-writeup/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 18 Jun 2018 13:47:38 +0800</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://tcode2k16.github.io/blog/posts/crossctf-final-2018-writeup/</guid>
      <description>Perfect Problem &amp;lsquo;Cause we lost it all Nothin&amp;rsquo; lasts forever
Creator - amon (@nn_amon) Update: this definitely works with python 2.7.15
perfect
Solution I went through the assembly code line by line converting it into something more readable:
local_420h = 2^213 get local_410h local_440h = int(local_410h, 10) - 1 local_430h = int(local_410h, 10) do { if (local_430h%local_440h == 0) { local_460h += local_440h } local_440h -= 1 } while (local_440h &amp;gt;= 0) if (local_460h == local_430h &amp;amp;&amp;amp; local_430h &amp;gt; local_420h) { // local_460h // WIN }  In summary, the program need a perfect number with a bit length larger than 213.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Microcorruption Writeup</title>
      <link>https://tcode2k16.github.io/blog/posts/microcorruption-writeup/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 12 Jun 2018 22:32:57 +0800</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://tcode2k16.github.io/blog/posts/microcorruption-writeup/</guid>
      <description>New Orleans - 10pts Here is the code for checking the password:
44bc: 0e43 clr	r14 44be: 0d4f mov	r15, r13 44c0: 0d5e add	r14, r13 44c2: ee9d 0024 cmp.b	@r13, 0x2400(r14) 44c6: 0520 jne	#0x44d2 &amp;lt;check_password+0x16&amp;gt; 44c8: 1e53 inc	r14 44ca: 3e92 cmp	#0x8, r14 44cc: f823 jne	#0x44be &amp;lt;check_password+0x2&amp;gt; 44ce: 1f43 mov	#0x1, r15 44d0: 3041 ret 44d2: 0f43 clr	r15 44d4: 3041 ret  It basically takes each byte and perform cmp.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Link Dump 2018 June</title>
      <link>https://tcode2k16.github.io/blog/posts/link-dump-2018-june/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 01 Jun 2018 09:53:55 +0800</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://tcode2k16.github.io/blog/posts/link-dump-2018-june/</guid>
      <description> Tech  lunr.js - an full-text search library for javascript Flutter Studio - a simple web interface for building flutter UIs Cool Backgrounds - a quick tool for generating cool backgrounds How to implement your own “Hello, World!” boot loader - intro to 80886 assembly and qemu VGABIOS.TXT - set bios video mode  DIY  Making of Mech Kitbash Making of Mech Kitbash #2  Cyber Security  Hacking Livestream #53: The ZIP file format - Zip file hacking corkami/pics - file format specs and posters  Tools  yafu - Automated integer factorization, great for cracking phi(n) in rsa NetworkMiner - only for windows, good for network forensics in ctf z3 - a theorem prover from Microsoft Research, great for RE angr - A powerful and user-friendly binary analysis platform, great for RE  </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>DC Generator Simulation</title>
      <link>https://tcode2k16.github.io/blog/posts/dc-generator-simulation/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 30 May 2018 11:15:48 +0800</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://tcode2k16.github.io/blog/posts/dc-generator-simulation/</guid>
      <description>final simulation   Here is the link to the simulation (use control key + mouse to move around).</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Barcode Scanner</title>
      <link>https://tcode2k16.github.io/blog/posts/barcode-scanner/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 30 May 2018 08:03:41 +0800</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://tcode2k16.github.io/blog/posts/barcode-scanner/</guid>
      <description>Development environment with vscode and iTerm   Problem There is a used-book sale program at our school, and currently, it is difficult to find books people want as books are not indexed and sorted properly. The maintainers all mentioned the experience of being asked wherever a specific book is within the large collection of books.
Solution I attempt to make an efficient system for indexing all the books and encourage more people to buy books they want from the book sale.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>SpaceLab Launch</title>
      <link>https://tcode2k16.github.io/blog/posts/spacelab-launch/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 22 May 2018 10:17:10 +0800</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://tcode2k16.github.io/blog/posts/spacelab-launch/</guid>
      <description>Photo Credit: NASA/Aubrey Gemignani   The project SpaceLab is a school program at the Singapore American School. The program allows students to create a space experiment that will be sent to the international space station for one month.
This is the second year of the program. A team of eleven students including me created a experiment that seeks to test the effect of micro-gravity on electro-plating copper.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Crossctf Qualifier 2018 Writeup</title>
      <link>https://tcode2k16.github.io/blog/posts/crossctf-2018-writeup/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 19 May 2018 13:05:55 +0800</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://tcode2k16.github.io/blog/posts/crossctf-2018-writeup/</guid>
      <description>QuirkyScript 1 Problem var flag = require(&amp;quot;./flag.js&amp;quot;); var express = require(&#39;express&#39;) var app = express() app.get(&#39;/flag&#39;, function (req, res) { if (req.query.first) { if (req.query.first.length == 8 &amp;amp;&amp;amp; req.query.first == &amp;quot;,,,,,,,&amp;quot; ) { res.send(flag.flag); return; } } res.send(&amp;quot;Try to solve this.&amp;quot;); }); app.listen(31337)  Solution According to the express.js docs, req.query.* can be an array.
Also, the code used == instead of ===; therefore, values of different types can be equal to each other and types are converted according to this:</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Vagrant virtual machine for CTF competitions</title>
      <link>https://tcode2k16.github.io/blog/posts/vagrant-vm/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 18 May 2018 11:28:59 +0800</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://tcode2k16.github.io/blog/posts/vagrant-vm/</guid>
      <description>Introduction I am running a cyber security club at my school. One of the club activities is to learn binary exploitation, most of my fellow club members don&amp;rsquo;t have linux installed on their computers and have little experience installing all the needed tools.
To make binary exploitation more accessible, I created this vagrant file that will setup all the necessary tools within a ubuntu virtual machine.
Method I picked vagrant over docker because of the follow reasons:</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Automated School Calendar</title>
      <link>https://tcode2k16.github.io/blog/posts/school-calendar/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 17 May 2018 08:45:01 +0800</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://tcode2k16.github.io/blog/posts/school-calendar/</guid>
      <description>Introduction I have finally got the chance to experiment with google apps script, and decided to use it to make my school life easier.
I used google apps script along with the calendar api to create a web app that can auto generate my class schedule based on another calendar provided by my school.

Method The script first pulls all the events from an existing calendar given a certain range for the date, and then it generates a new calendar.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>SHA1 Collision</title>
      <link>https://tcode2k16.github.io/blog/posts/sha1-collision/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 16 May 2018 11:32:16 +0800</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://tcode2k16.github.io/blog/posts/sha1-collision/</guid>
      <description>Introduction When I was doing the DEF CON CTF Qualifier last weekend, I came across an interesting question where you need to create two pdf files with the same SHA1 hash.
Research I know SHA1 hash was already broken when google blogged about creating the first SHA1 collision, but I was not sure that I can reproduce the process with limited hardware.
Result In the end, I came across this website that is able to generate two PDF files with the same SHA1 hash using two JPG images based on this paper.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>